Finding Aid for the Edwin Wendell Pauley Papers, 1907-2001
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Edwin Wendell Pauley Papers
1907-2001
435
Pauley, Edwin Wendell, 1903-1981
93 boxes (46.5 linear ft.) 6 shoe boxes 51 oversize boxes
Edwin Wendell Pauley was born in 1903. In 1940 Pauley served as a member of the University of California, Board of Regents, a position he kept for 30 years. The bulk of the collection consists of photographs, photo albums, and news clippings of Edwin Pauley with his family, friends, and numerous political figures of the twentieth century. Personal and political correspondence, correspondence and memorabilia from the 1960 Democratic National Convention, awards for public services, biographical information on Edwin Pauley, and books regarding political history are also included.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephen M. Pauley, Susan P. French, and Robert V. Pauley.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 5604262
Biography
Edwin Wendell Pauley was born in 1903 to Elbert L. Pauley and Ellen Van Petten. He received his Bachelor degree in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley in 1923 and soon thereafter began a successful career as an oilman. In 1940 Pauley served as a member of the University of California, Board of Regents, a position he kept for 30 years. He also served as a delegate from California at the 1944 Democratic National Convention and by 1960 he was the treasurer of the Democratic National Committee. After the war from 1945 to 1947, Pauley was the United States representative to the Allied Reparations Committee, serving and advising Presidents Truman, Kennedy, and Johnson. Pauley was first married to Norma Barrett. They had a son, Edwin Wendell Pauley, Jr. He later married Bobette J. McHenry (Bobbe) and had a daughter and two sons: Susan Jean, Stephen M., and Robert V. (Buzz). In 1947, Pauley and four other wealthy oilmen bought an island off the eastern coast of Oahu in Kaneohe Bay. Eventually, Pauley bought the other four shares and became the sole owner calling it Coconut Island where he and his family and friends spent many vacations together. After his death in 1981, the island was put up for sale by his wife and children, and eventually became the Hawaii Institute of Marine Biology.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection consists of photographs, photo albums, and news clippings of Edwin Pauley with his family, friends, and numerous political figures of the twentieth century. The rest of the collection includes personal and political correspondence, correspondence and memorabilia from the 1960 Democratic National Convention, awards for public services, biographical information on Edwin Pauley, and books regarding political history.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Awards
Biography of EWP (O.W. Van Petten)
Books
Business
EWP biography files
Herb Childs - Interviews - History - Information for Edwin W. Pauley Book - Bekins Files
Memorabilia
News clippings
News clippings albums
Personal
Photo albums
Photographs
Political files
Postcards
Scrapbooks
U.S. politics
University of California and U.S. Politics.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Pauley, Edwin W. (Edwin Wendell), 1903- --Archives.; Businessmen --California --Archival resources.; Politicians --United States --Archival resources.
Related Material
Edwin W. Pauley Papers, 1928-1996. Available at the Harold S. Truman Library and Museum.
Container List
- Awards
  - Lyndon B. Johnson certificate appointing EWP as member of Board of Trustees of the JFK Center for the Performing Arts (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Oversized
  - President of Finland Urho Kaleva Kekkonen to EWP as Commander, First Class, of the Order of the Lion of Finland (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Los Amigos del Pueblo - Founding Member and Trustee (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Oversized; Plaque
  - Los Amigos del Pueblo - Founding Member and Trustee (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - EWP - University of California Bachelor Degree of Science (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - YMCA Century Club to EWP (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Boys Scout of America Silver Beaver Award - San Gabriel Council to EWP (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Edwin W. Pauley Foundation Major Donor (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Western Airlines salutes EWP (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Congress of the United States Certificate of Appreciation to Mr. and Mrs. EWP (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Society of Former Special Agents to EWP (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Edwin W. Pauley Track - University of California, Santa Barbara (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Boys Club of Pasadena to Edwin W. Pauley Foundation (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Founding Four Hundred Pepperdine University (Box 117, Folder 8)
    Plaque
  - University of Hawaii Foundation - Barbara Pauley Pagen (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - City of Modesto - Distinguished Native of Modesto present to Mrs. Edwin W. Pauley (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Aloha to Bobbe Jean from the Propeller Club of the United States Port of Honolulu (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Distinguished Service Award Awarded to Barbara Pauley Pagen Presented by Bel-Air Council Navy League of the United States (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Aloha to Bobbe Jean from Governor George R. Ariyoshi (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - State of California Executive Department to EWP (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth of Kentucky to EWP (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - EWP - Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Lifetime Member of the Presidents Club presented by Continental Airlines - William R. Pagen (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - EWP honored for involvement with Los Angeles World Affairs Council (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 1)
    1 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 2)
    2 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 3)
    3 of 10; Bottom left corner repaired
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 4)
    4 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 5)
    5 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 6)
    6 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 7)
    7 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 8)
    8 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 9)
    9 of 10
  - California Yacht Club in Appreciation Commodore Bill Pagen (Box 124, Folder 10)
    10 of 10
  - Barbara McHenry Pauley - Endowed Child Chair UCLA Child Care Services (Box 130, Folder 1)
    Includes Model Chair and Base
  - Barbara Pauley Pagen - UCLA College of Letters and Science 1994 Honorary Fellow (Box 132, Folder 2)
    2 pieces, Crystal and wood base
  - From Vision Conservation Institute, Inc. to EWP (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - To Western Airlines on it's 40th Anniversary 1926-1966 Presented by the Boeing Company (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Committee of One Thousand - Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - County of Los Angeles to EWP (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - American Way of Life (The) - Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge (Box 135, Folder 3)
- Biography of EWP (O.W. Van Petten)
  - Correspondence of EWP and O.W. Van Petten 1969-1978 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and News Clippings
  - Various Clippings sent to EWP from O.W. Van Petten (Box 87, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, Magazine Clippings, and News Clippings
  - The Economist (Box 87, Folder 6)
    Magazine; Vol. 239, No. 6660
  - Sam Rayburn (Box 87, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, Photograph, and Pamphlet
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Drafts for Life and Times of EWP (Box 88, Folder 1)
    Correspondence
  - Life and Times of EWP (Box 88, Folder 2)
    Correspondence and Map
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter I (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter II (Box 88, Folder 4)
    f. 1 of 3
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter II (Box 88, Folder 5)
    f. 2 of 3
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter II (Box 88, Folder 6)
    f. 3 of 3
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter III (Box 89, Folder 1)
    f. 1 of 2
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter III (Box 89, Folder 2)
    f. 2 of 2
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter IV (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter V (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter VI (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter VII (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter VIII (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter IX (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter X (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter X (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Life and Times of EWP - Chapter XI (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Pauley Book - Childs and Van Petten (Box 90, Folder 5)
    Includes July 4, 1970 edition of The New Yorker
  - Herb Childs - Draft of Chapters II and III, War Booty? By P. Body (Box 90, Folder 6)
- Books
  - Self-Portrait: U.S.A. by David Douglas Duncan (Box 137, Folder 1)
    Oversized; with dust jacket
  - Future of Money (The) by Robert Hendrickson (Box 138, Folder 1)
    with dust jacket
  - Politics Battle Plan by Herbert M. Baus and William B. Ross (Box 138, Folder 2)
    with dust jacket and receipt 1968 Apr 16
  - There Was Light - Autobiography of a University Berkeley: 1868-1968 edited by Irving Stone (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - America and Russia in a Changing World by W. Averell Harriman (Box 139, Folder 1)
    with dust jacket and copy of news clipping LA Times 1971 Mar 17
  - Roosevelt - The Soldier of Freedom 1940-1945 by James MacGregor Burns (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Power of the Presidency (The) - Concepts and Controversy by Robert S. Hirschfield (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Vantage Point (The) - Perspectives of the Presidency 1963-1969 by Lyndon Baines Johnson (Box 140, Folder 2)
    with dust jacket; signed by LBJ; copy 1 of 2
  - Vantage Point (The) - Perspectives of the Presidency 1963-1969 by Lyndon Baines Johnson (Box 140, Folder 3)
    with dust jacket; signed by LBJ; copy 2 of 2
  - Gideon's army by Curtis D. MacDougall (Box 141, Folder 1)
    with dust jacket; volume 1
  - Gideon's army by Curtis D. MacDougall (Box 141, Folder 2)
    with dust jacket; volume 2
  - Gideon's army by Curtis D. MacDougall (Box 141, Folder 3)
    with dust jacket; volume 3
  - Ghost Talks (The) by Charles Michelson (Box 141, Folder 4)
    with note from Charles Michelson to EWP
  - David - Report on a Rockefeller by William Hoffman (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Wartime Journals of Charles A. Lindbergh (The) (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - Pensions or Penury? by Sheridan Downey (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Take Sunset Boulevard by Barbara and Rudy Marinacci (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Earl Warren - A Great American Story by Irving Stone (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Autobiography of Harry S. Truman (The) edited by Robert H. Ferrell (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Off the Record - The Private Papers of Harry S. Truman edited by Robert H. Ferrel (Box 143, Folder 4)
    with dust jacket and Correspondence from Corona Machmer to EWP 1980 Oct 28
  - An American Genius - The Life of Ernest Orlando Lawrence by Herbert Childs (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Coral Reef Population Biology edited by Paul L. Jokiel, Robert H. Richmond, and Rebecca A. Rogers (Box 144, Folder 5)
    Dedicated to EWP
  - United Nations Charter and Related Documents (Box 144, Folder 6)
    Volume 1
  - Report on Japanese Reparations to the President of the United States (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Report on Japanese Assets in Manchuria to the President of the United States (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Report on Japanese Assets in Soviet-Occupied Korea to the President of the United States (Box 145, Folder 3)
    Copy 1 of 2
  - Report on Japanese Assets in Soviet-Occupied Korea to the President of the United States (Box 146, Folder 1)
    Copy 2 of 2
  - Report on German Reparations to the President of the United States (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Report on German Reparations to the President of the United States (Box 146, Folder 3)
- Business
  - Braniff International Airways (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Oversized; Poster; More in b68_f2
  - Real Estate (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Oversized; Maps; More in b85_f3
  - Port Petrol (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Oversized; Poster; More in b63_f20
  - Pauley Pan American Petroleum Company (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Pauley Petroleum Inc. - the company (Box 45, Folder 7)
    Draft of company profile book
  - Pauley Petroleum Inc. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Pauley Petroleum Inc. - First Annual Report (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Andrew Haley (Box 84, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Booklets, and News Clippings; f. 1 of 2
  - Andrew Haley (Box 84, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, Booklets, and News Clippings; f. 2 of 2
  - Skiatron TV, Inc. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, Booklet, and News Clippings
  - Pauley Petroleum Inc (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Pauley Petroleum Inc (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Real Estate (Box 85, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Booklets, and News Clippings
  - Itinerary for Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Levy, Jr. (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - E.F. Hutton & Company (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Bache & Company (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Title Insurance & Trust Company (Box 85, Folder 7)
    Correspondence; Trust No. P-10219
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Henderson's Trust (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Sanford Independent School District (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Daniel Reeves & Company (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Johnson Lease Deal (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Edwin W. Pauley, Jr. - Athens Oil Corporation (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Fogelson Joint Venture, Montana (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Los Angeles Rams (Box 86, Folder 1)
    Correspondence, Pamphlets, and News Clippings; f. 1 of 2
  - Los Angeles Rams (Box 86, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, Pamphlets, and News Clippings; f. 2 of 2
  - H. R. Pauley - The Petrol Corporation (Box 86, Folder 3)
    Photographs and Correspondence
  - Panocal Petroleum Corporation - Minute Book (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Pico-Westwood Shopping Center (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Tobasco Area Joint Venture (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - The Petrol Corporation (Box 87, Folder 1)
    Minutes of the Board of Directors 1943-1945
  - The Fandango Corporation (Formerly The Petrol Corporation) (Box 87, Folder 2)
    Correspondence and Booklets; f. 1 of 2; Minutes of the Board of Directors 1946-1948
  - The Fandango Corporation (Formerly The Petrol Corporation) (Box 87, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and Booklets; f. 2 of 2; Minutes of the Board of Directors 1946-1948
- EWP Biography Files
  - President Ford Committee - Dinner - 1976 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and Speech Material - 1963 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - E.L. and Harold Pauley - Family History (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - William Monohan (Box 62, Folder 4)
    Correspondence; Herb Childs
  - Edwin W. Pauley (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Tapes - Pauley (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Carrie Derby Gardiner (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Katie Darragh (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Tapes (Box 62, Folder 9)
    Herb Childs
  - Testimonials for Ed (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Norma Pauley (Box 62, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, Photographs, and News Clippings; Herb Childs
  - J. R. Parten (Box 62, Folder 12)
    Correspondence and News Clippings; Herb Childs
  - Plane Accident - Thomas R. Rau (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Rams Partnership (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Lucian McCord Simpson (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Roman C. Warren (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Henry A. Wallace (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Justin R. Wolf (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Cal Tinney Show - 1958 Interview with EWP (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 1903-1917 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    Correspondence; EWP's semester grades
  - 1918-1923 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - 1923-Sept. 15, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Sept. 16, 1926-1927 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - 1928 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - 1929 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - 1930 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - 1931 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - 1932 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - 1933 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - 1934 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - 1935 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    Correspondence and Memorabilia
  - 1936 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - 1937 (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - 1938 (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - 1939 (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - 1940 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - 1941 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - 1943 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, Magazine Clippings, News Clippings
  - 1944 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - 1945 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - EWP - Notes - Petroleum Coordinator (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - 1968 (Box 64, Folder 7)
- Herb Childs - Interviews - History - Information for Edwin W. Pauley Book - Bekins Files
  - Andy and the Octopus - Transcript by Andy (John Anderson) at Coconut Island (Box 65, Folder 1)
    Copy 1
  - Andy and the Octopus - Transcript by Andy (John Anderson) at Coconut Island (Box 65, Folder 2)
    Copy 2
  - Andy and the Octopus - Transcript by Andy (John Anderson) at Coconut Island (Box 65, Folder 3)
    Original copy?
  - Bekins Files (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - R.E Allen. - Eureka - Pauley Oil Company (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - EWP - Biography (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - EWP - Bibliography (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley - Centennial Essay (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Jack B. Blalock (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Hawaii - Coconut Island - Honolulu race - Admiral Solomons (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - George Creel article - Big Tooth and Nail Man (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Claude L. Cameron (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Cole Committee - General (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - News Clippings (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Ralph K. Davies (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Admiral Robert L. Dennison USN (Retired) (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Regent Robert Augustus Dickson - Memorial Addresses (Box 66, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and Booklet
  - English Article (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Fogelson (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - James A. Fitzpatrick (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Gato Ridge - Golcanda (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - W. Averell Harriman (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - James L. Hayes (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Clinton M. Hester (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Henry Hopkins (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Orris R. Hedges (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Harold Judson - Dollar Line (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Ray Kerr (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Georgia Stanley Lunch (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Jim McCleery (Box 66, Folder 17)
    Correspondence and Pamphlet
  - Petrol Corporation - Bandini Boulevard - William Shun (Box 66, Folder 18)
    Photographs and Postcards; "return to Ray Kerr c/o Jim McCleery - Spence Air Photos
  - J. Paull Marshall (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Questions, Ideas (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 66, Folder 21)
    Magazines and Magazine Clippings
  - Mexican Projects (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - J. Howard Marshall (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Mexico (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - George E. Miller (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Mex Refinery (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Allan Nevins - text on nomination of Truman as VP (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Oil for Russ book quotes (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Governor Culbert L. Olson (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Palestine Problem (Box 67, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and Booklet; B'nai B'rith Messenger (The) in Oversized
  - Pauley Children (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - EWP and Gordon Sessions - Revision Coconut by Mr. J. R. Rowe (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Correspondence; 10 chapters
  - Biography of Edwin W. Pauley Volume 1 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Tidelands (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Herb Childs Manuscript (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Herb Childs Manuscript (Box 67, Folder 10)
- Memorabilia
  - Operation Castle - Official observers badge, certificate of participation, and correspondence from P. W. Clarkson (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Man of the Year certificate presented to EWP by the Fordham University Alumni Association, Southern California Chapter (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Senate, California Legislature, 1972 Regular Session Resolution Relative to commending Edwin W. Pauley (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of acknowledgement for EWP contributing to the Memorial Activities Center Project at UCLA from the County of Los Angeles (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Certificate from the Senate of the State of Hawaii recognizing Bobbe and family for contributing to the University of Hawaii and the Hawaii Institute of Marine Biology (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Political cartoon of EWP and Harry S. Truman by Jim Berryman for the Washington D.C. Evening Star (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Portrait of EWP - souvenir from Mexico City (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Oversized; Charcoal painting
  - Graduation Yellow Hood (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Graduation Purple Hood (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Framed Checks (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Who's Who in California certificate presented to EWP by the Who's Who Historical Society (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Ram Horror-Scope Cartoon from Jack Manning to EWP (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles Herald-Examiner - Pauley Kind To Bruins; Puffing Troy Rescued (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - $1000000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - $8026426.67 Check paid to Mexofina, S.A. De C.V. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - $13535476.28 Check paid to Pauley Pan American Petroleum Co. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - $925000 Check paid to Pauley Pan American Petroleum Co. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - $660000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - $1850000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - $350000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - $1475000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - $1000000 Check paid to Pauley Petroleum Inc. mounted on a plaque (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - $250000 Check paid to Pauley Pan American Petroleum Co. mounted on a plaque (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - $7300000 Check paid to Pauley Pan American Petroleum Co. and American Independent Oil Company De Mexico, S.A. De C.V. (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - $2005035.07 Check paid to Industrial Development Authority of the town of Culpeper, Virginia (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Founders Day Dedication Ceremony in appreciation to the Edwin W. Pauley Foundation founder of the new International Student Center (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Acrylic block of Pauley Petroleum Inc. publication (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Acrylic block of Child Care Services UCLA (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Acrylic block of Saint John's Hospital and Health Center coin (Box 127, Folder 3)
    "In appreciation of your generous support" on verso
  - JFK side profile on coin for Inauguration as President of the United States (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln Continental hood ornament on marble stand for Barbara M. Pauley (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - EWP Treasurer Delegate badge for the 1944 Democratic National Convention (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Belgian Medallion - Eendracht Maakt Macht L'Union Fait La Force (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Chinese Medal (Box 129, Folder 3)
    1 of 5; 1 in case, 1 loose
  - Chinese Medal (Box 129, Folder 4)
    2 of 5; In case
  - Chinese Medal (Box 129, Folder 5)
    3 of 5; In case
  - Chinese Medal (Box 129, Folder 6)
    4 of 5; In case
  - Chinese Medal (Box 129, Folder 7)
    5 of 5; In case
  - Ladies hat woven from native materials by Tesoro's in Manila, Philippines (Box 129, Folder 8)